A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Publications (Non-Grant Related), Accession 2017:050 FA1304
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Ford Foundation Publications, 1
  - Why Johnny Can't - The Problem of State School Financing, A Ford Foundation Reprint from National Journal, Rochelle L. Stanfield (2 copies), 1976 April 24 (Box 96, Folder 1148)
  - Higher/Wider/Education: A Report on Open Learning, Ronald Gross (2 copies), 1976 June (Box 96, Folder 1149)
  - Paying for Schools and Colleges, A Ford Foundation Report, Robert Tolles (2 copies), 1975 (Box 96, Folder 1150)
  - A Native American Challenge, A Ford Foundation Reprint from Juris Doctor (2 copies), 1976 (Box 96, Folder 1151)
    Articles - "Who Owns the Land" and "In Pursuit of Tribal Sovereignty," reprinted from 1976 issues of Juris Doctor
  - On the Job: A New Program for Opening Work to the "Hard Core" Unemployed (2 copies), 1976 (Box 96, Folder 1152)
    Select press reports and comment on the Supported Work program
  - Black Colleges and the Continuing Dream, A Ford Foundation Reprint, Harold Howe II (2 copies), 1976 April (Box 96, Folder 1153)
    Adapted from remarks given at the inauguration of Samuel DuBois Cook as president of Dillard University, New Orleans, April 3, 1976
  - Nine for Equality Under Law: Civil Rights Litigation, A Report to the Ford Foundation by Robert B. McKay (2 copies), 1977 April (Box 96, Folder 1154)
  - Human Resources and the Pendulum of Power, A Ford Foundation Reprint, Mitchell Sviridoff (2 copies), 1976 November (Box 96, Folder 1155)
    Talk given at the annual Connecticut Social Welfare Conference in New Haven, November 18, 1976
  - Soviet-American Scholarly Exchange: Should Learning and Politics Mix?, A Ford Foundation Reprint from Vital Issues, Felice D. Gaer (3 copies), 1980 June (Box 96, Folder 1156)
    Reprinted with permission from Vital Issues, Volume XXIX, Number 10, June, 1980, produced by The Center for Information on America, Washington, Connecticut
  - Women in the World: A Ford Foundation Position Paper (2 copies), 1980 November (Box 96, Folder 1157)
  - Healing the Heart of the Cities: Young Voices Speak Out, A Project of the Campus Outreach Opportunity League, Edited by Sean Dennis Cashman (2 copies), 1993 (Box 96, Folder 1158)
  - Toward a Strategy for Urban Integration: Lessons in School and Housing Policy, A Report to the Ford Foundation, Gary Orfield, 1981 December (Box 96, Folder 1159)
  - A Tale of Three Cities: Boston, Birmingham, Hartford, Ford Foundation Series on Higher Education in the Cities (2 copies), 1981 (Box 96, Folder 1160)
  - The Educational Endowment Series - Managing Educational Endowments: Report to the Ford Foundation, Second Edition, Advisory Committee on Endowment Management, 1972 July (Box 96, Folder 1161)
  - The Manpower Demonstration Research Corporation: Origin and Early Operations, Edward M. Brecher (2 copies), 1978 February (Box 96, Folder 1162)
  - The Evolution of the National Tenant Management Demonstration Program, Allan R. Talbot (2 copies), 1977 February (Box 97, Folder 1163)
  - Report on the Proceedings of the Public Interest Law Conference, San Diego, California, April 15-17, 1974 (2 copies), 1974 May (Box 97, Folder 1164)
  - A Foundation Decade: An Interview with McGeorge Bundy, A Ford Foundation Reprint from Black Enterprise (2 copies), 1975 September (Box 97, Folder 1165)
  - The Human Side of Productivity, A Ford Foundation Reprint, Basil J. Whiting (2 copies), 1974 December (Box 97, Folder 1166)
    Basil J. Whiting appeared before the Senate Committee on Government Operations on December 17, 1974, in response to its invitation to discuss some of the broader issues associated with this nation's lagging productivity.
  - Ford Foundation Assistance to Puerto Ricans (2 copies), undated (Box 97, Folder 1167)
  - La Raza: Ford Foundation Assistance to Mexican Americans (2 copies), undated (Box 97, Folder 1168)
  - The Educational Endowment Series - Measuring Investment Results by the Unit Method, A Ford Foundation Report (2 copies), 1975 (Box 97, Folder 1169)
  - Program-Related Investments: A Different Approach to Philanthropy (2 copies), 1974 (Box 97, Folder 1170)
  - Ford Foundation Experiments in Regional Environmental Management: A Symposium of the American Association for the Advancement of Science (2 copies), 1974 (Box 97, Folder 1171)
  - Patents and Collaboration Between the Private and Public Sectors, A Ford Foundation Reprint from the American Bar Association Journal, Sheila Avrin McLean (2 copies), undated (Box 97, Folder 1172)
  - 90-13: A World in Need of Leadership - Versions of Report and Background Papers (English, French, Spanish), 1990-1996 (Box 97, Folder 1173-1174)
  - A World in Need of Leadership - Original Faxes, 1990 (Box 97, Folder 1175)
  - A World in Need of Leadership - Press Packet, 1990 September (Box 98, Folder 1176)
    Includes black and white photograph of Brian Urquhart
  - A World in Need of Leadership - Printed Database of People Who Received Letter, 1990 (Box 98, Folder 1177)
  - A World in Need of Leadership - Correspondence, 1990 September - 1991 January (Box 98, Folder 1178-1179)
  - A World in Need of Leadership - Correspondence, 1990 February - September (Box 98, Folder 1180)
  - A World in Need of Leadership - Press and Hill & Knowlton Contract, 1990 (Box 99, Folder 1181)
  - A World in Need of Leadership: Tomorrow's United Nations, A Study Made Possible by the Ford Foundation and the Dag Hammarskjöld Foundation, National and International Coverage and Letters (2 copies), 1991 (Box 99, Folder 1182-1183)
  - Research - Ford Foundation Grants to Canadian Institutions FY1953 - FY1969, 1953-1969 (Box 99, Folder 1184)
  - Research - Ford Foundation Supported Citizen-Education Groups - Attachments B & C, 1967 (Box 99, Folder 1185)
  - Research - Education, Special Program in Education - Addenda, Includes Drafts, 1965 June 18 (Box 99, Folder 1186)
  - Research - Education - Teacher Training - Part I, 1962-1966 (Box 99, Folder 1187)
  - Research - Education - Teacher Training - Part II, 1966 (Box 99, Folder 1188)
    Includes a rough draft of the addenda for the "New Teacher" publication; School Improvement Program Conference, Fort Lauderdale, Florida, Fact Sheets on Projects Supported by the Ford Foundation, January 1966; and Foundations, Schools, and the Public Good pamphlet, Edward J. Meade, Jr.
  - Research - Education, Vocational and Technical, 1965 (Box 100, Folder 1189)
    Includes Phi Delta Kappan Journal, April 1965, Volume XLVI, No. 8 and descriptions of Ford Foundation grants for vocational and technical education
  - Research - Engineering - Ford Foundation Grants, 1958-1965 (Box 100, Folder 1190)
  - Research - Fellowship Programs, 1962-1966 (Box 100, Folder 1191)
  - Research - Film Production - All Programs, 1967 (Box 100, Folder 1192)
  - Research - Ford Foundation - History, Activities, Finances, General Information, 1965-1967 (Box 100, Folder 1193)
  - Research - Ford Foundation Grants to Jewish and Israeli Organizations FY53 - FY69, 1972 (Box 100, Folder 1194)
  - Research - Housing, Building, and Planning - Ford Foundation Grants through 1969, 1966-1969 (Box 100, Folder 1195)
  - Research - Grants To and Concerning Labor Unions, 1969 (Box 100, Folder 1196)
  - Research - Library Development, 1955-1967 (Box 100, Folder 1197)
  - Research - Negro Education Part 1, 1951-1966 (Box 100, Folder 1198-1199)
  - Research - Negro Education Part 2, 1964-1966 (Box 100, Folder 1200, Box 101, Folder 1201)
  - Research - Negro Education Part 3, 1960-1967 (Box 101, Folder 1202)
  - Research - New York City Grantees FY1953-FY1968, 1966-1969 (Box 101, Folder 1203-1204)
  - Research - Non-Commercial TV 1951-1969 May, 1964-1969 (Box 101, Folder 1205)
  - Research - Public Affairs - Crime, Criminology, and the Administration of Justice, 1953-1967 (Box 101, Folder 1206)
  - Research - Public Affairs - General File, 1955-1967 (Box 101, Folder 1207)
  - Research - Public Affairs - Gray Areas Program, 1961-1967 (Box 101, Folder 1208)
  - Research - Public Affairs - Law, International Law, or Public Administration, 1951-1964 (Box 101, Folder 1209)
  - Research - Public Affairs, Urban Affairs, Extension, 1961-1967 (Box 102, Folder 1210)
    Includes listing of Ford Foundation Urban and Regional Program Grants 1955-1961 and contains papers regarding the Urban Affairs Program - Conference Program in Metropolitan Affairs First Conference, April 2-14, 1967
  - Research - Requests and Blank Forms, 1966-1967 (Box 102, Folder 1211)
  - Research - Requests, 1968 (Box 102, Folder 1212)
  - Research - Science - Ford Foundation Grants, 1950-1966 (Box 102, Folder 1213)
  - Research - World Statistics - Population, Health, Enrollments, etc., 1961-1964 (Box 102, Folder 1214)
  - Job 92-01: Violence Against Women, 1992 (Box 102, Folder 1215)
    Contains papers detailing publication processes and press materials
  - Job 92-01: Violence Against Women - Lists File, 1992 (Box 102, Folder 1216-1218)
  - Job 92-08: Towards A More Effective United Nations - List Information, 1992-1994 (Box 103, Folder 1219-1221)
  - Job 92-08: Towards A More Effective United Nations (Printout of UN Database Lists Used) (Box 103, Folder 1222)
  - Job 92-10: Strategic Communications for Nonprofits, 1992-1993 (Box 103, Folder 1223)
  - Job 92-19: Innovations in State & Local Government - 1993 General, 1992-1994 (Box 103, Folder 1224)
  - Job 92-19: Innovations in State & Local Government - 1993 Winners - Press Releases, 1993-1996 (Box 103, Folder 1225)
    Includes Press Release from October 20, 1993 - Vice President Gore Hails 1993 Innovations in State and Local Government Award-Winners at Washington, D.C. Ceremony
  - Job 92-19: Innovations in State & Local Government - 1993 Finalists - Press Releases (Box 104, Folder 1226)
  - Job 92-19: Innovations in State & Local Government - 1993 Semifinalists - Press Releases (Box 104, Folder 1227)
  - Job 92-20: Latino Fact Book, 1992 (Box 104, Folder 1228)
    Includes press releases with information regarding a survey conducted by the Latino National Political Survey (LNPS)
  - Readings on Family Planning and Population Program Management: Background Papers for a Ford Foundation Meeting on Population, Elsinore, Denmark (2 copies), 1972 June (Box 104, Folder 1229-1230)
  - Readings on Population Information and Education: Background Papers for a Ford Foundation Meeting on Population, Elsinore, Denmark (2 copies), 1972 June (Box 104, Folder 1231, Box 105, Folder 1232)
  - The Finances of the Performing Arts Volume II: A Survey of the Characteristics and Attitudes of Audiences for Theater, Opera, Symphony, and Ballet in 12 U.S. Cities, A Report to the Ford Foundation Prepared by Eric Marder Associates, Inc. (2 copies), 1974 (Box 105, Folder 1233)
  - Urbanization in India, International Urbanization Survey, The Ford Foundation, 1971 (Box 105, Folder 1234)
  - Urbanization and Government Policy in Morocco, Katherine Marshall Johnson, International Urbanization Survey, The Ford Foundation, 1971 (Box 105, Folder 1235)
  - Urbanization in Morocco: An International Urbanization Survey Report to the Ford Foundation, 1971 (Box 105, Folder 1236)
  - Urbanization in Brazil, James A. Gardner, International Urbanization Study, The Ford Foundation (2 copies), 1971 (Box 105, Folder 1237)
  - Urbanization in Thailand: An International Urbanization Survey Report to the Ford Foundation, Jeff Romm, 1971 (Box 106, Folder 1238)
  - Infrastructure Problems of the Cities of Developing Countries: An International Urbanization Survey Report to the Ford Foundation, undated (Box 106, Folder 1239)
  - Education in the Sciences, Equity and Excellence: Compatible Goals, Shirley M. Malcolm, American Association for the Advancement of Science (2 copies), 1984 December (Box 106, Folder 1240)
    An Assessment of Programs That Facilitate Increased Access and Achievement of Females and Minorities in K-12 Mathematics and Science Education, Contract Period: April 1-July 31, 1983, A Study Conducted for the NBS Commission on Precollege Education in Mathematics, Science, and Technology, Office of Opportunities in Science, American Association for the Advancement of Science
  - Intervention Programs in Math, Science, and Computer Science for Minority and Female Students in Grades Four through Eight, Beatriz Chu Clewell, Margaret E. Thorpe, and Bernice Taylor Anderson, Educational Testing Service, Princeton, New Jersey (2 copies), 1987 May (Box 106, Folder 1241)
    This directory was supported by the Ford Foundation under Grant No. 860-0255
  - Innovations in State and Local Governments 1991 - Exhibit (Box 106, Folder 1242)
    - Innovations in State and Local Governments 1991 - Exhibit Blueprints, 2017:050:005 (Box Separated, Item 2017:050:005)
  - Innovations in State and Local Government 1991 - Photo Shoot - Documents (Box 106, Folder 1243)
    Includes photography contracts, contact information for the 1991 award recipients, and itineraries
  - 1991 Annual Report Photo Research - Reproductive Health, 1991-1992 (Box 106, Folder 1244)
  - 1991 Annual Report Photo Research - Program-Related Investments, 1991-1992 (Box 106, Folder 1245)
    Related to East Baltimore Housing homesteading project, Seedco project; Includes a copies of Investing in America's Neighborhoods: Providing for America's Future and Coastal Enterprises, Inc. 1991 Annual Report
  - 1991 Annual Report Photo Research - International Affairs, 1992 (Box 106, Folder 1246)
  - 1991 Annual Report Photo Research - Education & Culture, 1991-1992 (Box 106, Folder 1247)
  - 1991 Annual Report Photo Research - Rights & Social Justice, 1991-1992 (Box 106, Folder 1248)
  - 1991 Annual Report Photo Research - Governance & Public Policy, 1990-1992 (Box 106, Folder 1249)
    Includes copies of Newsletter of the Hispanic Community Fund of the Bay Area from Summer 1990 and Summer 1991
  - 1991 Annual Report Photo Research - Rural Poverty, 1992 (Box 106, Folder 1250)
  - 1991 Annual Report Photo Research - Urban Poverty, 1989-1992 (Box 107, Folder 1251)
    Includes a copy of the Shorebank Corporation's 1989 Annual Report and correspondence with Public/Private Ventures
  - America Becoming - Documents, 1991 (Box 107, Folder 1252)
    America Becoming is 90-minute documentary special presented by WETA, Washington, D.C. that profiles new immigrants in the US.
  - In Her Own Image: Films and Videos Empowering Women for the Future, 1991-1992 (Box 107, Folder 1253)
  - Neighborhood Housing Services of Cleveland: Preserving Urban Neighborhoods, undated (Box 107, Folder 1254)
  - Photos - Annual Report 1992 - Documents (Box 107, Folder 1255)
  - Current Interests of the Ford Foundation 1990 and 1991 - Documents, 1990-1991 (Box 107, Folder 1256)
    Includes two final copies of Current Interests of the Ford Foundation, 1990 and 1991
  - Current Interests of the Ford Foundation 1992-1993 - Design Documents, 1991-1992 (Box 107, Folder 1257)
  - Current Interests of the Ford Foundation - Print Quotations, 1992 (Box 107, Folder 1258)
  - Current Interests of the Ford Foundation - Documents, 1992 (Box 107, Folder 1259)
  - Budget for New Publications - Innovations, 1991 (Box 107, Folder 1260)
  - Samples/Dummies - MDRC, undated (Box 107, Folder 1261)
    Samples related to a Manpower Demonstration Research Corporation (MDRC) publication?
  - Working Women: A Portrait of South Africa's Black Women Workers and Correspondence, 1985 (Box 107, Folder 1262)
    Original folder title difficult to read - South Africa - Daneha Wales (Sp?)
  - Overseas Education Fund of the League of Women Voters, 1982-1986 (Box 107, Folder 1263)
  - Slide Descriptions - Bangladesh Women's Health Coalition/Afhad University College for Women Rural Extension Program, 1985-1986 (Box 107, Folder 1264)
  - Supplements for The Shape of Our Cities - The Reality of Change 1-1a, undated (Box 107, Folder 1265)
  - Supplements for The Shape of Our Cities - The Growth and Scale of Cities 2-2a, undated (Box 107, Folder 1266)
  - Supplements for The Shape of Our Cities - The Individual and the Family 3-3a, undated (Box 108, Folder 1267)
  - Supplements for The Shape of Our Cities - The Family and the Community 4-4a, undated (Box 108, Folder 1268)
  - Supplements for The Shape of Our Cities - Man and the Automobile 5-5a, undated (Box 108, Folder 1269)
  - Supplements for The Shape of Our Cities - Meeting Places of the Community 6-6a, undated (Box 108, Folder 1270)
  - Supplements for The Shape of Our Cities - The Urban Region 7-7a, undated (Box 108, Folder 1271)
  - Supplements for the Shape of Our Cities - The Residential Section 8-8a, undated (Box 108, Folder 1272)
  - Supplements for the Shape of Our Cities - From Utopia to Reality 9-9a, undated (Box 108, Folder 1272)
  - Supplements for the Shape of Our Cities - The Shape of Our Cities Tomorrow 10-10a, undated (Box 108, Folder 1273)
  - Discussion Leader's Guide For Use with Exploring the Ways of Mankind by Walter Goldschmidt, 1961 (Box 108, Folder 1274)
  - Transition and Tension in Southeast Asia, Nathaniel Peffer, 1957 (Box 108, Folder 1275)
  - Ways of Mankind: Adult Discussion Series - "How People Live Together Different Times and Places," Walter Goldschmidt, Experimental Discussion Project of The Fund for Adult Education, 1954 (Box 108, Folder 1276)
  - The Ways of Mankind: A Discussion Guide and Readings, Harry L. Miller, The Center for the Liberal Education for Adults, 1953 (Box 108, Folder 1277)
  - The Ways of Mankind: A Series of Experimental Discussion Programs, Discussion Leader's Guide, The Fund for Adult Education, 1954 (Box 108, Folder 1278)
  - The Ways of Mankind: A Discussion Leader's Guide, The Fund for Adult Education, 1958 (Box 108, Folder 1279)
  - Readings in The Ways of Mankind: Discussion Leader's Guide, The Fund for Adult Education, White Plains, New York, 1957 (Box 108, Folder 1280)
  - Ways of Mankind: An Adult Discussion Program, 1955 (Box 108, Folder 1281)
  - Working Papers Series Redesign - Design Documentation, 1988-1989 (Box 109, Folder 1283)